Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute Ukrainian Cylinder Collection, 1908-1930s
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series II: Sound Recordings
  - Untitled song: female group singing Пісня без назви: жiночий гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 125.1 Cylinder index number: 35/185
  - Untitled song: female group singing Пісня без назви: жiночий гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 125.2 Cylinder index number: 35/185
  - Untitled song: female group singing Пісня без назви: жiночий гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 125.3 Cylinder index number: 35/185
  - Duma of the enslaved Дума невольника Sung by an unidentified performer Duma, voice, solo Song index number: 126.0 Cylinder index number: 35/187
  - "The Black Sea Played" "Заграло Чорне Море" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, voice, solo Song index number: 126.1 Cylinder index number: 35/187
  - Narration Оповiдання Sung by an unidentified performer Declamation, voice, solo Song index number: 127.0 Cylinder index number: 35/188
  - Untitled song: male solo singing Пісня без назви: мужеський сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song, voice, solo, male Song index number: 128.0 Cylinder index number: 35/203 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR20)
  - Untitled song: male group singing Пісня без назви: мужеський гуртовий спів Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 128.1 Cylinder index number: 35/203
  - Untitled song: male group singing Пісня без назви: мужеський гуртовий спів Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 128.2 Cylinder index number: 35/203
  - Untitled song: male group singing Пісня без назви: мужеський гуртовий спів Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 128.3 Cylinder index number: 35/203
  - "This Is Our Ukraine" "Ото наша Україна" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 129.0 Cylinder index number: 35/247
  - "This Is Our Ukraine" "Ото наша Україна" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, voice, solo, male Song index number: 129.1 Cylinder index number: 35/247
  - "This Is Our Ukraine" "Ото наша Україна" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, voice, solo, male Song index number: 129.2 Cylinder index number: 35/247
  - "This Is Our Ukraine" "Ото наша Україна" Unknown Song, fiddle, male Song index number: 129.3 Cylinder index number: 35/247
  - "This Is Our Ukraine" "Ото наша Україна" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, voice, solo, male Song index number: 129.4 Cylinder index number: 35/247
  - "This Is Our Ukraine" "Ото наша Україна" Sung and played by an unidentified performer Song, voice and fiddle, male Song index number: 129.5 Cylinder index number: 35/247
  - "The Cuckoo Cuckooed" "Закувала зозуля" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 129.6 Cylinder index number: 35/247
  - Untitled composition for accordion Пісня без назви: гра на баяні Sung and played by an unidentified performer Song, accordion Song index number: 129.7 Cylinder index number: 35/247
  - "He Drank His Sheep Away" "Пропив вiвцi при горiвцi" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 130.0 Cylinder index number: 35/262
  - "Ivan Came to Marija" "Прийшов Iван до Марiйки" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 130.1 Cylinder index number: 35/262
  - "On Saturday I Gave Birth, on Sunday I Babtized" "В суботу ся родила, в недiлю Хрестила" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 130.2 Cylinder index number: 35/262
  - "People Say that I am Drunk" "Кажуть люди що я впився" Sung by an unidentified performer Song. solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 130.3 Cylinder index number: 35/262
  - "Again, and Again" "I ще раз, i ще раз" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 130.4 Cylinder index number: 35/262
  - "Oh, Ivan, Ivanochku" "Ой, Iване, Iваночку" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 130.5 Cylinder index number: 35/262
  - "I Cut My Wrist and It Hurts" "Порубала ручку, та болить" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 130.6 Cylinder index number: 35/262
  - Narration Оповiдання Sung by an unidentified performer Declamation, solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 131.0 Cylinder index number: 29 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR21)
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 132.0 Cylinder index number: 30
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 132.1 Cylinder index number: 30
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 132.2 Cylinder index number: 30
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 132.3 Cylinder index number: 30
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 132.4 Cylinder index number: 30
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 132.5 Cylinder index number: 30
  - Untitled song: male solo singing Пісня без назви: мужеський сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 133.0 Cylinder index number: 547
  - Untitled song: male solo singing Пісня без назви: мужеський сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 133.1 Cylinder index number: 547
  - Untitled song: male solo singing Пісня без назви: мужеський сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 133.2 Cylinder index number: 547
  - Untitled kolomejka (ditty): female solo singing коломийка без назви: жiночий сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song: kolomejka, solo, voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 134.0 Cylinder index number: 4 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR22)
  - Untitled kolomejka (ditty): female solo singing коломийка без назви: жiночий сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song: kolomejka, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 134.1 Cylinder index number: 4
  - Untitled kolomejka (ditty): female solo singing коломийка без назви: жiночий сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song: kolomejka, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 134.2 Cylinder index number: 4
  - Untitled kolomejka (ditty): female solo singing коломийка без назви: жiночий сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song: kolomejka, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 134.3 Cylinder index number: 4
  - Untitled kolomejka (ditty): female solo singing коломийка без назви: жiночий сольоспiв Sung by an unidentified performer Song: kolomejka, solo voice, a cappella, female Song index number: 134.4 Cylinder index number: 4
  - Untitled song (duma): male solo singing Дума без назви: мужеський сольоспiв без супроводу Sung by an unidentified performer Duma, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 135.0 Cylinder index number: 151
  - Untitled song: male solo singing Пісня без назви: мужеський сольоспів без супроводу Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 135.1 Cylinder index number: 151
  - Untitled song: male solo singing Пісня без назви: мужеський сольоспів без супроводу Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 135.2 Cylinder index number: 151
  - Untitled song: group singing Пісня без назви: гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 136.0 Cylinder index number: 7
  - Untitled song: group singing Пісня без назви: гуртовий спiв Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 136.1 Cylinder index number: 7 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR23)
  - Solo singing, excerpt of the duma about an orphan girl Сольоспiв, уривок Думи про сирiтку Sung by an unidentified performer Duma, voice, solo Song index number: 137.0 Cylinder index number: 35/6
  - Solo singing, continuation of duma about an orphan girl Сольоспiв, продовження Думи про сирiтку Sung by an unidentified performer Duma, voice, solo Song index number: 138.0 Cylinder index number: 35/7
  - Female solo singing, Keening Жiночий сольоспiв, Голосiння Sung by an unidentified performer Keening, voice, solo Song index number: 139.0 Cylinder index number: 35/9
  - Playing the hurdy-gurdy, two dances Гра на лiрi, два танки Sung and played by Nazar Poklad Dance, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 140.0 Cylinder index number: 35/10
  - Playing the hurdy-gurdy, two dances Гра на лiрi, два танки Sung and played by Nazar Poklad Dance, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 140.1 Cylinder index number: 35/10
  - Instrumental for bandura: dance Гра на бандурi: танок Played by an unidentified performer Dance, bandura Song index number: 141.0 Cylinder index number: 35/11
  - Instrumental for bandura: dance Гра на бандурi: танок Played by an unidentified performer Dance, bandura Song index number: 141.1 Cylinder index number: 35/11
  - Instrumental for bandura: dance Гра на бандурi: танок Played by an unidentified performer Dance, bandura Song index number: 141.2 Cylinder index number: 35/11
  - Instrumental for bandura music: dance Гра на бандурi, один танок Played by an unidentified performer Dance, bandura Song index number: 142.0 Cylinder index number: 35/12
  - Psalm about Oleksi, Man of God Псальма про Олексiя, Божого Чоловiка Sung and played by Samson Vesely Psalm, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 143.0 Cylinder index number:35/47
  - Psalm about Eremu and Khomu Псальма про Єрему i Хому Sung and played by Samson Vesely Psalm, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 143.1 Cylinder index number: 35/47
  - Duma about a sister and a brother (beginning) Дума про Сестру та Брата (початок) Sung and played by Samson Vesely Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 144.0 Cylinder index number: 35/48
  - Duma about a sister and a brother (continuation) Дума про Сестру та Брата (продовження) Sung and played by Samson Vesely Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 145.0 Cylinder index number: 35/49
  - Psalm about Oleksi, Man of God Псальма про Олексiя, Божого чоловiка Sung and played by Samson Vesely Psalm, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 146.0 Cylinder index number: 35/51
  - Psalm about an orphan "Of What am I Guilty" Псальма сиротина "Що я кому винуват" Sung and played by Nestir Kolisnyk Psalm, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 147.0 Cylinder index number: 35/52 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR24)
  - [this may be a copy of another cylinder], singing and playing the hurdy-gurdy Це можливо копiя iнчого валика. лiрник Саливон Веселий у супроводi лiри Sung and played by Salyvon Vesely [?] voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 148.0 Cylinder index number: 35/53
  - Duma about a widow and three sons (continuation) Дума про вдову i трьох синiв (продовження) Sung and played by Nestir Kolisnyk Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 149.0 Cylinder index number: 35/55
  - Duma about a widow and three sons (continuation) Дума про вдову i трьох синiв (продовження) Sung and played by Nestir Kolisnyk Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 150.0 Cylinder index number: 35/56
  - Duma about a widow and three sons (continuation) Дума про вдову i трьох синiв (продовження) Sung and played by Nestir Kolisnyk Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 151.0 Cylinder index number: 35/57
  - Duma about a sister and brother Дума про Сестру та Брата Played by Makar Duma, bandura, male Song index number: 152.0 Cylinder index number: 35/71
  - Psalm about Lazarus Псальма про Лазаря Sung and played by an unidentified performer Psalm, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 153.0 Cylinder index number: 35/78
  - Untitled duma with instrumental accompaniment Сольоспiв лiрника у супроводi лiри, дума Sung and played by an unidentified performer Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 154.0 Cylinder index number: 35/79
  - Psalm about Mykhaiila Псальма про Михаўла Sung by Iivha Hrushchenko Psalm, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 155.0 Cylinder index number: 35/84 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR25)
  - Female group singing, song about Bazylevsʹky Жiночий гуртовий спiв, пiсня про Базилевських Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 156.0 Cylinder index number: 35/122
  - Song about the kozaks from Turbaiiv Пiсня про Турбаўвських козакiв Sung by Maksym Movchan Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 157.0 Cylinder index number: 35/124
  - Song about Salyvon Пiсня про Саливона Sung by Samson Vesely Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 158.0 Cylinder index number: 35/125
  - Group singing teamster song Гуртовий спiв, чумацька пiсня Sung by unidentified performers Song: teamster song, choir Song index number: 159.0 Cylinder index number: 35/126
  - "Oh, You Vagabond Kozak, Your Mind is Unwise" "Ой, козаче-бурлаче, та дурний розум маєш" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 159.1 Cylinder index number: 35/126
  - Untitled song: duet singing Пісня без назви: дует Vasyl and Petro Dovhani Song, voice, duet, male Song index number: 160.0 Cylinder index number: 35/128 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR26)
  - Untitled song: duet singing Пісня без назви: дует Sung by Vasyl and Petro Dovhani Song Song index number: 160.1 Cylinder index number: 35/128
  - Sopilka/folk flute music Інструментальний твір для сопільки Sung and played by Vasyl and Petro Dovhani Instrumental, sopilka (folk flute) Song index number: 160.2 Cylinder index number: 35/128
  - Untitled song Пісня без назви: дует Sung by Vasyl and Petro Dovhani Song, voice, duet, male Song index number: 160.3 Cylinder index number: 35/128
  - Group singing, carol Гуртовий спiв, коляда Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: koliada (winter), choir Song index number: 161.0 Cylinder index number: 35/130
  - Sopilka/folk flute tune: "Drunkard's Song" Дiд Лукаш, гра на сопiлцi, "Пяницька" Played by Grandpa Lukash Instrumental song, sopilka (folk flute), male Song index number: 162.0 Cylinder index number: 35/131
  - "Oh, I Told One Girl" "Ой, казав однi дiвцi" Played by Grandpa Lukash Instrumental song, sopilka (folk flute), male Song index number: 162.1 Cylinder index number: 35/131
  - "In the Time of Joy" "В час радостi" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 163.0 Cylinder index number: 35/207
  - "The Angels Descended" "Се сходжуть ангели" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 163.1 Cylinder index number: 35/207
  - "The Eternal One" "Превiчний родився" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 163.2 Cylinder index number: 35/207
  - "The Beautiful Star Came" "Iшла звiзда красна" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 163.3 Cylinder index number: 35/207
  - "News in Bethlehem" "В Вифлеємi новиа" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 163.4 Cylinder index number: 35/207
  - Group singing, carol Гуртовий спiв, колядка Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: koliada (winter), choir Song index number: 164.0 Cylinder index number: 35/208
  - Group singing, carol Гуртовий спiв, колядка Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: koliada (winter), choir Song index number: 164.1 Cylinder index number: 35/208
  - Group singing, carol Гуртовий спiв, колядка Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: koliada (winter), choir Song index number: 164.2 Cylinder index number: 35/208
  - Ladkannia: ritual wedding praise Ладкання Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: ladkannia (wedding), choir Song index number: 165.0 Cylinder index number: 35/213
  - "When I Reminisce" "Коли собi погадаю" Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: ladkannia (wedding), choir Song index number: 165.1 Cylinder index number: 35/213
  - "It Is Hard for Young Me" "Тяжко менi молоденькi" Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: ladkannia (wedding), choir Song index number: 165.2 Cylinder index number: 35/213
  - "Oh, There Is a Red Elderberry Tree in the Meadow" "Ой, у лузi червона калина" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 166.0 Cylinder index number: 35/214
  - "Oh, in the Field" "Ой, у полi" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 166.1 Cylinder index number: 35/214
  - "Mountain Valley, Mountain Valley" "Полонина, полонина" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 166.2 Cylinder index number: 35/214
  - "Kolomeya" "Коломея" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 166.3 Cylinder index number: 35/214
  - "Oh, Give God to Me" "Ой, дай Боже до нас" Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: wedding, voice, duet, male/female Song index number: 167.0 Cylinder index number: 35/217
  - Wedding praise Ладкання Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: wedding voice, duet, male/female Song index number: 167.1 Cylinder index number: 35/217
  - Wedding praise Ладкання Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: wedding, voice, duet, male/female Song index number: 167.2 Cylinder index number: 35/217
  - "The Sapling Grew" Гуртовий спiв, три пiснi: "Росло деревце" Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: winter, choir Song index number: 168.0 Cylinder index number: 35/218 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR27)
  - "A New Joy Came" "Нова радiсть стала" Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: winter, choir Song index number: 168.1 Cylinder index number: 35/218
  - "Good Evening, It Is Good" "Добрий вечiр, добрий" Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: winter, choir Song index number: 168.2 Cylinder index number: 35/218
  - "Your Birth" "Рождество Твоє" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 169.0 Cylinder index number: 35/221
  - "Oh God, Give Everything" "Ой, дай Боже все" Sung by unidentified performers Ritual song: wedding (ladkannia), choir, female Song index number: 169.1 Cylinder index number: 35/221
  - "Rejoicing, We Sound Today" "Лукующе возграєм днесь" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 170.0 Cylinder index number: 35/225
  - "Cherubim Song" "Хорувими свiт" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 170.1 Cylinder index number: 35/225
  - "When You Are by Me" "Як Ти бiля мене" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 170.2 Cylinder index number: 35/225
  - "Swim, Duck, Swim" "Пливи, качко, пливи" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 171.0 Cylinder index number: 35/226
  - "The Sapling Grew" "Росло деревце" Song, choir Sung by unidentified performers Song index number: 171.1 Cylinder index number: 35/226
  - "In the Time of Joy" "В час радостi" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella Song index number: 171.2 Cylinder index number: 35/226
  - "Oh, the Fair-Skinned Girl Walked" "Ой, ходила бiла дiвка" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 172.0 Cylinder index number: 35/229
  - "Black Fortune Is Not Desirable" "Чорна гора не хороша" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 172.1 Cylinder index number: 35/229
  - "Across, Across" "На поперек, поперек" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, female Song index number: 172.2 Cylinder index number: 35/229
  - "Oh, She Walked Through the Garden" "Ой, ходила по садочку" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 173.0 Cylinder index number: 35/230
  - "Joyous News for the World" "Весела свiту новина" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, solo voice, a cappella, male Song index number: 173.1 Cylinder index number: 35/230
  - "The Eternal Is Born" "Предвiчний родився" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 174.0 Cylinder index number: 35/233
  - "In the Town of Nazareth" "У мiстечку Назаретi" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir Song index number: 174.1 Cylinder index number: 35/233
  - "The Messiah Will Come" "Прийде Месiя" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 174.2 Cylinder index number: 35/233
  - "Jesus Christ Is Born" "Народився Iсус Христос" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 174.3 Cylinder index number: 35/233
  - "Joyous News for the World" "Весела свiту новина" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 174.4 Cylinder index number: 35/233
  - "Your Birth" "Рождество Твоє" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 175.0 Cylinder index number: 35/234
  - "In the Country of Judea" "Востране Юдейський" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 175.1 Cylinder index number: 35/234
  - "Saviour Is Born" "Народився Спаситель" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 175.2 Cylinder index number: 35/234
  - "Oh, there Is a Willow on the Hill" "Ой, на горi верба" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 175.3 Cylinder index number: 35/234
  - "Grey Volyky" "Сивi волики, сивi" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 176.0 Cylinder index number: 35/241 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR28)
  - "Plantane Tree in the Village" "Серед села яворина" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 176.1 Cylinder index number: 35/241
  - "Pretty Evening" "Гарний вечiр" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 176.2 Cylinder index number: 35/241
  - "The Blond Girl Went for Mushrooms" "Бiла дiвка на гриби ходила" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 176.3 Cylinder index number: 35/241
  - "Through the Winding Shore" "Через крутi бережечки" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 176.4 Cylinder index number: 35/241
  - "I Work on a Collective Farm" "В колгоспi працюю" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 177.0 Cylinder index number: 35/243
  - "Among the Winding Carpathian Mountains" "Серед гiр крутих Карпатських" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 178.0 Cylinder index number: 35/245
  - "The Blackthorn Tree Will Blossom" "Зацвiть терен" Sung by unidentified performers Song, choir, male Song index number: 178.1 Cylinder index number: 35/245
  - Kolomeyka Коломейка Sung by unidentified performers Kolomyika, voice, ensemble Song index number: 179.0 Cylinder index number: 35/246
  - Kolomeyka Коломейка Sung by unidentified performers Kolomyika, voice, ensemble Song index number: 179.1 Cylinder index number: 35/246
  - Kolomeyka Коломейка Sung by unidentified performers Kolomyika, voice, ensemble Song index number: 179.2 Cylinder index number: 35/246
  - Kolomeyka Коломейка Sung by unidentified performers Kolomyika, voice, ensemble Song index number: 179.3 Cylinder index number: 35/246
  - "On the Carpathian Mountains" "На горах Карпатських" Sung by unidentified performers Kolomyika, voice, ensemble Song index number: 179.4 Cylinder index number: 35/246
  - Song with bandura accompaniment Одна пiсня у супроводi бандури, Nosach, song, voice, bandura, male Song index number: 180.0 Cylinder index number: XIII